2 lovers, one summer, and the 9 songs that defined them.
9 Songs is a drama, music, romance film directed by Michael Winterbottom.
Matt, a young glaciologist, soars across the vast, silent, icebound
immensities of the South Pole as he recalls his love affair with Lisa.
They meet at a mobbed rock concert in a vast music
hall - London's Brixton Academy.
They are in bed at night's end.
Together, over a period of several months, they pursue a mutual sexual passion whose
inevitable stages unfold in counterpoint to nine live-concert songs.
Matt, played by Kieran O'Brien.
Lisa, played by Margo Stilley.
Himself - The Dandy Warhols (uncredited), played by Courtney Taylor-Taylor.
Himself - Franz Ferdinand (uncredited), played by Alex Kapranos.
Himself - Elbow (uncredited), played by Guy Garvey.
Himself - Black Rebel Motorcycle Club (uncredited), played by Robert Levon Been.
9 Songs is a 2004 British erotic art film written
and directed by Michael Winterbottom.
The film stars Kieran O'Brien and Margo Stilley.
The title refers to the nine songs played by eight rock
bands that complement the story of the film.
The film was controversial upon original release due to its sexual content, which included unsimulated footage of the two leads,
Kieran O'Brien and Margo Stilley, having sexual intercourse and performing oral sex as well as a scene of ejaculation.
The film was showcased at the Cannes Film Festival.
The film explores themes of london, england,
concert, rock 'n' roll, sexuality, orgasm.
The tone is emotional and intense.